"Cannes Film Festival - Out of Competition"
"Opening Film"
(Jean Du Barry)
Jeanne Faubernier was the illegitimate daughter
of a monk and a cook.
Her destiny was to live among the common people,
or as they say, the common people or the people.
It could be said that it was worthless.
But aren't worthless women
willing to do anything?
Her mother, Anne, raised her alone from birth.
Her employer, Mr. Domoso, was
a generous and kind person
Out of love for the girl,
he borne the costs of her education.
He quenched her thirst for knowledge
and improved her morals by allowing her to attend his meetings.
Thought.
- Perception.
I did well.
The idea.
- Thinking.
I did well.
- Logic.
Mindfulness.
the decision.
Knowledge.
Comprehension.
Acumen.
Well done, Jan.
Thanks to Mr. Domoso
who borne all the costs,
Jeanne joined the Monastery of Saint-Ore.
There is no doubt that he wanted to spare her from the life full of adultery
that commoner girls often lived.
Come on, Jan.
Jan has grown up.
The monastery life became annoying to her.
But the books she was reading broadened her horizons.
I soon learned the disturbing effect
of the sex drive.
Jan"!
O sinner!
I will teach you how to read books on this topic.
Lower your head.
Yes?
When she graduated from the monastery, Jean was not young.
Fearing that her husband would not resist the girl's beauty,
Madame Domusso expels Jeanne and her mother,
accusing them of a theft they did not commit.
But what good is self-exoneration
when others want to falsely accuse you?
The two women traveled to Paris,
the capital of all dreams and dangers.
Jan, how long will it take?
- Take off your clothes.
no.
Come here.
Jan, please take off your clothes.
I don't understand why you always act differently.
This is my body.
- Leave her alone.
Sorry?
Go for a walk in the park. she is beautiful.
Shortly thereafter,
Jean became Madame de la Garde's reader.
A widow who lives alone with her two sons.
That lady introduced Jean to literature.
Jeanne soon competed
with the elite of the aristocracy.
No shame.
Insolence.
Impudence.
Is there another one?
Daring.
Recklessness.
I did well.
- Rudeness. Your turn, Jan.
Riot.
After everything I've done for you, I find you fucking my two sons?
Go away, you slut!
shame on you. You must feel ashamed.
Thanks to debauchery,
Jean knew how to become a woman while remaining free.
Years passed,
Jean learned to use her beauty
to seduce wealthy lovers.
She soon became known as a prostitute.
And here is Adelaide
in her pink satin dress
Underneath this black silk is a white corset,
For feminine sweetness, for teenage sweetness.
- It's Du Barry.
How are you sir?
- I'm fine, are you?
- Mr. Du Barry.
- Miss.
nice to meet you.
- The honor is mine.
How are you?
I thank you.
- Is it delicious?
I'm Jan.
And I'm John.
You are an angel from heaven.
Madame Labbe told a lot about you,
and it is clear that she did not lie.
Where were you all that time?
I have been waiting for you.
You are not afraid of anything.
I already made you laugh.
-Don't you believe me?
Yes.
What should I do to make you believe me?
-I can offer you a place to stay.
- The marriage takes place with my mother’s approval.
There is no problem between me and your mother, but I am here...
I risk my life.
me too.
- Let's share our lives then.
- What's your response?
-I agree.
Good. I like this.
so we have agreed.
Monsieur du Barry,
despite all the respect I have for you,
I express my appreciation to you, Count.
These are words from a Duke.
I appreciate you too.
I'm all ears.
You know,
we always send women to the king's bed.
Okay.
No woman liked him.
exactly.
well now...
He should meet King Jan.
They must meet by chance.
-You're betting on coincidences then.
exactly.
He will think he chose it himself.
Here it is.
Where have you been, my dear? I was waiting for you.
- I was helping Adolphe with his French article.
-I have people to help him.
There are things that cannot be bought, Du Barry.
- "Du Barry" without a master?
Yes.
Who's here tonight?
As usual, writers, poets
and Marshal de Richelieu.
Come, I want you.
There are also royal mistresses
and Miss Loughran.
And Countess de la Reina.
- Couldn't you resist?
-You have lovers too.
Yes, but my lovers contribute to the costs of our house,
but your lovers do not contribute.
Or we can break up and fuck whoever you want.
Jean, de Richelieu wants to introduce you to the King.
- Never stop talking about the king.
- The decision to go is yours, Jan.
I'm here for your son.
Jean, my love.
I love you.
I may not love you as much as you want, but I love you.
-This is not love.
truly? So what is it?
Tell me, you who know everything.
I may not know what love is
, but I know that it is not this.
good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
- Good evening, ma'am.
This is the apple of my eye.
"Adolf."
The wine is delicious.
actually.
- Good night, gentlemen.
- Good night, Adolf.
good night.
Epiphany cake.
I know it's your favorite cake.
What?
I have something in my mouth.
Without being rude, this is your habit.
redundant.
- Your mouth is full.
The king has a beautiful face.
Are you still showering?
You told me to rest.
Yes, you are right.
It's important to rest.
But you know you have to tell me all your relationships.
I'm talking to you.
Why do you always read?
Aren't you comfortable? Relax. Come on, relax.
You're a stupid bitch and you're going to be that way until you die.
I do not agree to meet anyone else in the morning.
I will meet the others in the evening.
Be careful, a beautiful lie
is a confession of love.
Jan, don't you think it's time
to change your life?
Where to go?
and with who?
I can't leave his son Adolf.
John wants me to introduce you to the king.
I know, he talks to me about it day and night.
Jean, what life do you want?
A life full of curiosity.
A life in which we can
live, drink, eat, write and read.
As you know, people like me can't do anything.
My mom is a cook.
Or I will be like her...
Or build relationships.
I prefer relationships.
Turn around.
the king!
For my brother who is sentenced to death.
My lord.
- “The concept of...”
- the feudal lord.
Sorry, "feudal lord".
- "Feudal".
Good morning, ma'am.
good morning sir.
His Majesty would like to meet Mrs.
Good. when?
Now, if it is suitable for a lady.
-It will be ready within an hour.
- No, I'm ready.
what do you mean?
I am ready.
No, it's not right for you to go like this.
At least change your dress or style your hair.
- Say something, Anne.
- He's right, change your dress.
Be beautiful as always.
You are hers.
Do not be afraid.
I'm not afraid.
What is this?
- That's how things go. No one should see you.
Jan",
when you will come back?
I will not be late.
- Have you established relationships with many people?
- What do you mean by "many"?
more than one person.
I have a relationship with one man at a time, yes.
Most of the times.
Do you have any pain in the uterus?
I do not understand.
- He asks if you suffer from vaginal itching.
no.
Every day I oil...
He charmed me with the most expensive oils.
Don't you feel a burning sensation while urinating?
While snoring.
no.
I'm sorry I have to examine you more carefully.
Good.
- Please lie down.
Would you please spread your legs apart, ma'am?
More yet, ma'am.
thus.
- The lady can go to the king's bed.
Good.
my lord...
I suggest we put her in quarantine for a few days
to watch for any venereal disease.
Thank you, but that's enough.
And now what? You'll taste me, right?
no.
no?
It is said that you taste women
before sending them to the king.
I have to teach you some habits now.
Good.
-Do you always talk like this?
-So how?
- I mean by this condescension.
- But you are in Versailles, ma'am.
I can't talk to the king like that.
I think the king did not ask you to hear you.
Well, teach me the customs of Versailles.
Will you show me how you'll bow to the king tonight?
Raise your arms higher.
I did well.
-Should I touch him first?
- Let him guide you.
Good.
-Is he difficult to please?
- No, the least satisfies him.
You don't need a thousand positions to arouse him.
but...
Should I say something special?
Your rush is enough.
The only thing you need to know, ma'am,
is that you must never turn your back on the king.
If the king is in front of you and you want to turn around,
you should do the following...
Is this a joke?
Absolutely.
No one should turn his back on the king
except the Dauphin.
Understood?
Yes.
but...
What if I don't back down?
His Majesty will see that you are an insolent.
and what?
- He is sensitive to rudeness.
me too.
What are you laughing at, ma'am?
I laugh because you look like what you look like on a six-franc coin.
It is an honor to meet you, Your Majesty.
Take a glass of champagne.
Can I taste it?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Do you like it?
no.
-Is this pure gold?
Yes.
Is your name engraved on every fork and spoon?
I think so.
Is it gold that catches your attention?
Look behind you, there.
The statue.
Okay. Is it gold too?
I apologize, Your Majesty.
I apologize, Your Majesty, but I can't do it.
did what?
Step back a little.
I'm sorry I can't back out.
-What's your sign?
I don't know.
I don't believe in astrology, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Excuse me?
- By what?
- Not to back down.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Is this you?
Is this your honor when you were young?
Please, would you let your hair down?
Your command, Your Majesty.
my lady?
Will you get dressed?
Immediately.
I have to wear my dress.
Follow me.
progressive.
Wait for me here, ma'am.
My lord, it's time.
Your Majesty, the first doctors.
Your Majesty, the first to attend.
Royal family.
Your Majesty, Senior Officers of the Crown.
Your Majesty, your clothes.
Your Majesty, wigs.
Ladies and gentlemen, the King's wake has ended.
The royal family can leave.
The Dauphan.
-Does this happen every day?
Yes.
Every day the same people come
and repeat the same things?
Yes.
close your eyes.
Open them.
Can I open it?
I would like you to stay here in Versailles.
Do you also want to stay?
Absolutely.
I'll see you later.
Good.
I apologize to you.
Who are all those with the king?
The fat one standing next to the king
He is Choiseul, the Prime Minister.
Malice radiates from his eyes.
Does he really want his sister to sleep with the king?
I don't know, ma'am.
But you know really well.
Oh my God, it's the Dauphan.
How handsome he is.
Who are all these women?
They are His Majesty's daughters,
Adelaide, Sophie, and Victoire.
That hunchback is Louise,
the king's favorite daughter.
Her nickname is "The Last".
- Bring me pork.
pork.
this?
- No, pork.
I rarely see women this ugly.
And will the queen never appear?
She doesn't like to be seen.
Because she suffers from her husband's betrayal.
Like all the queens of France.
The king loves her sobriety, humility, and kind heart.
All of France knows what's up.
The king betrays her in the palace
and the “Park au Serre” garden.
The Queen cares more about her children and religion.
She does not like luxuries
or those who do not manage their money well
Quickly cover your head and lie down.
We would like to leave. Move!
Your order, I will move.
Queen Maria Leszczyńska died
after 43 years of rule out of sight.
Leaving the road wide for Jan.
But mourning and etiquette
kept her outside Versailles in a secret room.
My lord, they are your daughters. They know you exist.
Your dress.
Come here.
Good day, my girls.
Our Father...
A shameful rumor spreads in the Palace of Versailles.
As usual.
Father, it is said that you spend your nights with...
My dear daughters...
Sometimes your father is with a girlfriend.
This is correct.
But she's married...
- She has a son.
- There is no title for that woman.
She is definitely not married and that is her lover's son.
- It's unknown.
- I disagree with you.
We have become the future of Versailles because of your immorality.
Father, our mother just died
and we want you to be considerate of our feelings.
- The conversation is over.
my dad?
I cannot bear for you to have a relationship with that woman
while we are mourning our mother.
And so are we.
My lord, Choiseul knew Jean's lineage.
It will not be acceptable for a commoner girl
to be in your entourage.
That young woman is my entourage.
Your command, my lord.
I want to be by her side
When the sun rises
And when it sets.
this is what I want.
- Your command.
So you know what to do.
faster.
Your command, my lord.
To be officially accepted into the court,
Joan needed a husband and a noble family title.
Jean Du Barry agreed to marry her
in exchange for a large sum of money.
Sir, Comte du Barry,
- Do you accept Jean Bernier...
- Faubernier.
-Jean Faubernier is your wife?
Yes.
Mademoiselle Jean Faubernier,
will you accept Jean de Barry as your husband?
Yes.
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
The two rings, Adolf.
Shall I not kiss the bride?
Thus, Jeanne became Countess du Barry.
Grand Canal, Minor Canal,
Trianon Palace, forest,
flower garden, French garden,
Orangery, Palace of Versailles.
600 water fountains and 200 thousand trees.
I did well.
Who lives in the court, from lowest to highest?
Servants, officers, courtiers, the royal family.
At what time does His Majesty walk
through the Hall of Mirrors to the church?
- At six?
no.
This was the first time
you met His Majesty. Do you remember?
And he meets me there.
exactly.
I think it's a quarter to ten.
I did well.
- Because Mass is at ten.
the rest of the day?
At eleven, the Council of Ministers.
At one o'clock in the afternoon, he had lunch in his room
With a family member or alone.
He spends his afternoon hunting animals
Or take a nap.
dinner?
- Dinner is at six.
Unless there is an opera.
And when he calls the courtiers,
They eat a little after the servant tastes it
The King's Forty Dishes.
correct
Who eats standing and who eats sitting?
Dukes eat sitting,
counts and countesses standing.
-You're moving fast.
-Does this mean they'll watch me eat?
Yes.
Even eating while standing is considered a privilege for the courtiers.
Let's move on to the three bows of greeting.
This is the most important thing. Good.
Your approach will be severely criticized.
I'm King. look at me.
Don't look into my eyes.
No matter what happens, never look into the king's eyes.
Good.
What did you just say?
- Lower your eyes.
- What if I don't lower them?
If you do not reduce them,
the court will consider you arrogant to the king.
They consider you arrogant.
Or on the contrary, they will consider you claiming the king.
- Call him?
Yes.
What should I invite him to?
Good...
They will consider you claiming it.
-What should I invite him?
-You invite him to...
You understand me, ma'am.
no.
indeed.
-What should I invite him?
- Establishing a relationship.
You make me laugh.
-Can I laugh in court?
- One does not show one's feelings in court.
Let's move on.
Imagine this is the hem of your dress.
Step back to the door.
I walked on it.
progressive. I'm the King of France,
and the entire court is watching.
anything new?
I don't know.
She won't be late.
- The king's patience began to run out.
- Pretty girls are always late.
Your Majesty, may I
admit the Countess du Barry?
Enter it.
Countess Jeanne du Barry!
finally.
What a slut.
-What are you thinking?
- Aren't you ashamed?
Ladies and gentlemen, please take a seat
to see the gift presented by His Majesty the King
To the Countess du Barry.
gift?
“All my days and nights my mind
is rarely clear and my mind is often busy
The fire of love ignites me and its flame is in my heart
“I am in love, and the sky does not see a lover happier than me.”
Oh, my God.
I thank you.
What is your name?
- “Zamor.”
You must be from a far country.
you are welcome here.
I thank you.
Do not be afraid. Do not be afraid.
- Welcome, Zamor.
I thank you.
Bow to the king. Bow down to him.
Look at her.
Aren't you ashamed?
Ma'am, here's your room.
This room is all yours.
Jan, I introduce you to your hairdresser, make-up artist,
butler, servants and chambermaids.
Please.
No no. What do you do?
Backed by the love of the king,
Jeanne imposed on the Palace of Versailles
her love of simplicity and the arts.
Many artists and poets benefited from this.
I knew that it was decided to marry the Dauphin
and that he was somewhere in Austria,
An 11-year-old girl named Marie Antoinette
seeks to propose to him.
Fortunately for Jean,
she became the first lady of the palace court.
But how long will it last?
The king can choose another girl
in Parc au Ser and fire Jeanne for the slightest mistake.
How beautiful you are.
What a divine secret.
Is there something wrong, ma'am?
Only the stars matter to you, Your Majesty.
How much I love you when you are upset.
you are wrong. You love me all the time.
This is correct.
I love you, ma'am.
No, Your Majesty, you do not love me.
- What excites you is that you don't know me.
-But I know you.
She is dressed like a man.
I hope you don't forget your friend.
- I'm not the queen.
not yet.
On her first official outing,
Jeanne appeared arm in arm with the King.
For the first time at the French court,
A woman breaks the custom of wearing headpieces
and wigs and dresses like a man.
Even though you have achieved the rank you sought,
I am worried about you.
- What if the king gets tired of you?
- This is far from happening.
Don't be so arrogant. Arrogance may waste you.
But, Jean, what about Park or Ser?
Know. He no longer goes to her.
- But the garden is there, and this is dangerous for you.
-It's not dangerous at all.
Madame de Pompadour
is the one who built the garden to satisfy his lust.
And with your presence, he no longer
needs to satisfy her outside, right?
exactly. Unlike some.
If he didn't resist you to this extent,
why didn't he marry you?
Because that's how we'll have to break up.
The clergy do not accept this.
His great-grandfather married his mistress.
Why doesn't he do the same to you?
Because my mind is more preoccupied with Zamor.
He has no one but me.
Want a house in your name and your own wealth,
and don't worry about a Negro boy.
His name is Zamor.
I thank you.
"Lovesin."
Finally, Jan had a place
In it, she can entertain her beloved king
without anyone telling her what to do.
- How boring.
- Please wait a little while.
You can both come in.
Please.
Where is he from?
Chandernagore in Bengal.
Do niggers live there?
He is definitely from Africa
but he passed through India.
I think it was sold more than once.
- Now he lives in France.
-I think her dress is beautiful.
It's planned.
It looks like curtain fabric.
You said he now lives in France.
I made it my page.
For God's sake, the page reflects your white color.
The page reflects your nobility.
Although one does not have to be a noble
to remain at court.
is not it?
-He's my servant now.
- You mean your slave?
is not it?
both.
It is clear to him that life directed him towards slavery.
In America, that little nigger
will harvest the sugar cane.
Here he offers you tea and chocolate.
That's all he does.
Nothing more should be expected from him.
Even he himself couldn't expect more.
He, like all of God's creatures, can be redeemed.
- "Louise"?
What?
Are you telling me now about Christian education?
Although we are different,
he is my brother in the love of Christ.
And your brother too, and so do you.
And you.
I agree with you.
She agrees.
-Do you want a biscuit?
- "Louise"...
Take.
He is black in skin
but has a pink tongue like ours.
I did not notice.
Is it delicious? Yes?
That's right, his tongue is pink.
I have to leave.
Allow me, my sisters.
Let's sing. Shall we continue the track?
Yes.
It's over.
They are lowly.
Wounded by shame, Louise left Versailles.
She gave up her title and privileges
and joined the monastic order.
The king's last daughter was close to his heart,
and her departure depressed him.
- My lord, Countess du Barry.
Good.
Will you accompany me?
I want us to be alone.
Is the fate of Louise something that concerns you?
I should work.
my regards.
Sorry?
"my regards"?
Yes. my regards.
- Who did you stay up with at night?
- Madame de Briche.
Mostly at Versailles.
Her husband is a musician.
Does the king have other mistresses?
Madam, you are the king's favorite
, but the king likes change.
The unknown attracts its majesty.
If I'm falling out of his sight,
you'd better tell me so I can leave.
You are beginning to discover the dark side of the King.
You must keep fit and brave.
Am I doomed to be loyal?
Your behavior should not be in doubt.
Your enemies magnify every mistake and make it trivial
before the king
Laborde was right.
Jan shouldn't worry.
It was still his favorite.
Despite the ridicule of her striped clothes
and men's clothing,
However, the ladies of the court
were enthusiastically imitating her and slandering her.
Look. That...
It's "du Barry" fashion.
Joan spent four happy years with the king,
who slowly regained his zest for life.
Zamor grew up,
and thanks to Jan, he became a polite and educated young man.
Jeanne fell in love with Adolf,
who had recently arrived at court.
Concerned about his future,
she arranged his marriage to a girl
From the high bourgeois class, she attracted him.
its enough. Stop, Adolf.
Stop.
I got better but...
But it was another wedding that caused a stir.
Finally, the Dauphin, heir to the throne, married
the young woman, Marie Antoinette, from Austria.
The arrival of the future queen,
meticulously planned by Choiseul,
To a state of turmoil in the court.
Jan became threatened.
- Look at her skin.
Oh my God, white as cream.
"Louis"?
Do you speak a little German?
no.
Can I teach it to you?
maybe later.
Merci"?
Madam, the Dauphine is hungry.
When will she be served food?
As soon as the king entered.
Of course, okay.
Thank you, Mercy.
Your Majesty!
And Countess du Barry.
She is wearing a white dress.
Hey Victoire.
Her hair is down.
How terrible. This is terrible.
This terrible.
How dare they? How dare they?
In front of that girl.
- Who is that beautiful?
- She's a common girl.
We have to get rid of them, and we are counting on you to do so.
-I'm thinking about leaving the table.
- Look.
I can't stand to see that.
It is shameful for the king to present
this creature to the Dauphin.
This is not worthy of a Christian king.
It is clear that tonight
we will celebrate the end of that creature.
Du Barry neither loves nor hates anyone.
- This cannot be the character of a countess.
- Look.
This woman has a quality
that Madame de Pompadour lacked.
- It's about that thing.
anything?
The thing between the crotch, my dear lady.
My dear, you must use your power
to remove that awful woman from court.
The more you ignore that creature,
the more the kingdom will love you.
I've told my father everything that's on my mind before,
but he's stubborn.
Perhaps your word will have a greater impact.
-He loves you very much.
-I love him too.
This creature has no right to speak to you
until you speak to it first.
You know this, right?
In this case, I declare myself her opponent.
I thank you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
In the name of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Madam, Adolf was defeated in a duel.
He is seriously injured and the vehicle is ready.
Jan has not gotten over the death of Adolf,
her beloved son whom she did not have.
Comfort and luxury became boring and useless to her.
She knew that what remained for her in Versailles
was the king's love for her.
The future queen still ignores her.
This weakens Jan's position at court.
Stop.
New role.
- Well, it's...
- 14, 12.
no.
indeed.
‫- 15، 12.
‫- 13، 13.
- 13, 13?
Yes...
Don't let their bullying get the best of you.
Well, Your Majesty.
I will do everything in my power
to bring My Lady the Dauphine to her senses.
Good.
The Dauphine will speak to you tomorrow.
At four in the afternoon, in the gambling hall.
Here's what will happen.
I will warn you.
With a look, a word, or a sign.
Then the Dauphine will stand up after me and tell you something.
You will say meaningless words.
Don't expect formal talk from her.
Valdauphine prefers improvisation.
I understand you.
That would be great.
I wish Adolf had been there.
He would have been happy for me.
And...
I want one of you to choose a card.
- Any card he wants.
- I will choose.
- Queen of Sabbath.
usually...
Show card.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that would be none other than the Queen of Spit. Thanks.
- Choose a card, ma'am.
- The ace of the ace.
You chose the hairstyle because my hair is heart-shaped.
Thank you very much.
It's time for a music lesson.
the king!
Your Majesty, I...
Your Majesty, the union between France and Austria
is at stake.
You have to give her a word.
What a poor Mercy.
He did his best.
I think Mercy's right, but you're not, Adelaide.
Sufi".
What an idiot.
Your Majesty...
Madame Dauphine wishes to invite Your Majesty
For a play in which you play the role of a shepherdess.
Beautiful.
A shepherdess.
Will Your Majesty honor us by attending?
no.
May I have a reason, Your Majesty?
I don't want.
Don't want to. naturally.
Well, Your Majesty.
My full respect to you.
There are many people in the palace today.
but why?
Why?
- I addressed a word to you.
Why did you talk to her? Why?
- She's running.
- She's running!
She addressed me with a word.
- She directed a word to me.
Good.
She addressed me with a word.
- She looks happy.
- Yes, she looks happy.
Five words said by Amira
saved Jan from shame.
Finally the royal family deigned
to acknowledge her.
The happiness of lovers could have lasted,
But unfortunately, the stars that
the king loved to observe had a different opinion.
- I think we should tell him.
- You're lucky, Duke.
It is necessary to shed his blood for the third time.
Jan"...
They want to spill his blood for the third time.
Yes? Your command, my lord?
- Where is Jan?
-It exists. "Jan"?
Yes?
I am thirsty.
- No, I want fish water.
- Fishy water.
Thanks, Zamor.
He has smallpox.
Does he know the king?
That might kill him.
You are in danger, ma'am.
If the king dies, the royal family will kick you out.
Pack your bags.
no.
-It's just a minor setback.
- By the age of 64, smallpox is fatal.
definitely.
-We shouldn't tell the king.
I agree with you. This will make his condition worse.
Let me in.
Your Majesty, smallpox is contagious.
-I want to see my grandfather.
- My job is to protect you both.
- This is hideous.
no.
These are the rules of Versailles.
They gave me a mirror.
Show me how I'm doing.
I want to confess.
My lord...
To prove your remorse, you must stop shaming.
I fear hell, Jan.
I owe it to God and my people.
You have to leave.
Light the candle.
Give me this.
- “Felicity”?
- Your order, ma'am?
Can you make sure the candle is lit?
Yes, it's on fire.
I thank you.
Go to the monastery. This is all she deserves.
- What a relief. Do you want her to leave?
- And her fate is miserable.
Jan"!
- No, she's coming back.
- The creature is returning.
I didn't imagine this.
- I want to say goodbye to him.
no.
- Speak.
-Tell her something.
- Madam, I have already said goodbye to him.
Okay.
Enter it.
Your command, my lord.
I will accompany you.
I love you.
And finally you said it.
I love you too, Jan.
great love.
Jan"...
my dear.
Thank you, my lord.
You've always treated me well.
Don't worry, Zamor. Everything will be fine.
See you soon.
I absolve you of all your sins.
The king ordered me to inform you that he asked for the Lord's scoop for him
For the abuse and shame he caused his people.
And if the Lord returns him whole,
He will atone for his sins, support the religion, and provide relief for his people.
Take care of her, Laborde.
Your command, my lord.
You're my friend, Laborde.
- The king is dead! The king is dead!
- Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
The king is dead!
- Long live the king!
I...
I am at your service.
- Long live the king!
Joan was condemned
because she defended the church and the monarchy
Which was a sin.
She spent a year in the monastery.
Until Louis XVI released her
on the condition that she would not approach Versailles again.
Jeanne moved to Lovcen
and lived in peace for 15 years.
But the revolution broke out
, ended the privileges, and re-divided the wealth.
The nobles stopped their petty quarrels.
In the face of adversity,
Marie Antoinette offered her friendship to Jean.
In those turbulent times
everyone had to choose one of two classes.
Zamor sided with the Republic.
Out of necessity or spite,
he betrayed his former lover.
The fact that she wasn't a noble
didn't change anything.
In the eyes of the citizens,
Jean had betrayed her origins long before.
Louis XVI was beheaded
on January 21, 1793.
The head of "Marie Antoinette" on October 16.
"Jan" headed on December 8.
It is said that her last words
at the guillotine were:
“Just a moment, Mr. Executioner.
I loved life too much to let
it be taken away from me like this.”
Before she raised her head to the sky
for the last time.
“ I never made this film
or the previous ones,
Without the help of my friend Herve Tamim.
He was my supporter and I dedicate this film to him.”